From the Marvelous Designer 2024 version, you can turn on multiple wind control devices.
Through this function, you can create a more diversified wind blowing environment.
Go to the display environment icon in the 3D window, click to display the wind control device.
On the right-click on the wind control device icon, select copy, you can copy a wind control device.
You can adjust the position of the copied wind control device, rotate and set the value according to your needs.
After setting, record the animation and check the effect.
Through multiple wind control devices, we simulated the animation effect of the jellyfish floating.
When creating a wind control device, open the wireless border to make it blow wind at an unlimited range.
If you close the wireless border, the wind blowing effect will only work within the range marked by the wind control device.
You can manually release the wind blowing function.
Through the video capture function, you can quickly capture the animation played in the 3D window and save it as a video.
You can find the video capture tool in the animation video capture or in the animation editor on the main menu.
First, go to the animation editor settings, set the animation playback area, then click the video capture button and click capture.
Video capture will be carried out according to the previously set playback area.
After opening the video capture button,
the video capture button will turn into a stop button.
Through this button, you can stop the video capture at any time.
After the recording is over, the video will be automatically played in the default playback software.
The software model simulation function can more realistically show the transformation of the model's skin tone.
We currently only support the default virtual model of Marvelous Designer.
If you need to use the software model for custom virtual models, you need to use the automatic virtual model function.
Later, we will introduce how to use this function for you.
Now, we first select the virtual model in the 3D window and go to the property editor to see the software model simulation.
Set the software model intensity.
The smaller the value, the softer the skin.
When activating the software model simulation, a icon will appear in the lower right corner of the 3D window.
This icon will remind you that it is being activated.
After opening the model simulation, you will see that the skin is entangled by the bandage and a little concave.
When the software model simulation is turned on and the animation is recorded,
you will see that the software model simulation will be recorded as a separate animation layer.
You can export this animation to the Alembic format.
Through the automatic virtual model simulation function,
you can convert the virtual model created in other software into the default virtual model in Marvelous Designer.
Click on the main menu, virtual model, automatic virtual model simulation.
Open an AVT, OBJ or FBX file in the window.
Select the appropriate default virtual model according to gender and age.
In the conversion option, you can choose to automate or self-define.
The MD skin type will remain the body shape of the original model.
The neck appearance will be converted to the default virtual model appearance and the joint points will be increased.
The neck bone structure will be increased on the basis of maintaining the body shape of the original model and the appearance.
The size and editing will change the body shape of the model and the joint points will be increased,
so that the model can be transformed into a virtual model that can be used as a virtual model editor to modify the virtual model in various parts of the model.
Click on the conversion, you will see the virtual models generated by your image in the 3D window.
Now your virtual model has been converted and can use the functions that Marvelous Designer default virtual models can use, such as software model simulation.
The Everywhere function can connect the creator's digital costume to all virtual models and digital spaces.
Creators can easily optimize the digital costumes made for various digital spaces in Marvelous Designer through Everywhere.
For example, web page optimization, UV fill, and logic preparation.
Please set your goal, the total number of web pages, according to your needs.
Click on the optimization button, your costume web page will be optimized according to the input value.
For the optimization of the attached or buttoned web page, please select the attached or go to the physical window to select the type of button.
Then go to the attribute editor, select the bottom multi-sided web page optimization function, enter the target web page number in the number.
Then the attached button will be optimized according to the input value.
Selecting plane will make it turn into a plane and display it as a sticker.
If you want to use the four-sided web page, please select the middle version, find the web page in the attribute editor, and select the four-sided optimization option in the drop-down menu.
Next is the content of the Google binding.
Click on the application button of the Google app under the costume label.
You can automatically bind the costume to Google.
Then there will be an update and brush button.
Click on the brush button to switch to the brush window so that you can adjust the Google binding.
Press the Ctrl key to click on a joint point.
You can see the joint point.
You can see the weight related to the joint point.
You can place the weight on the 2D or 3D window.
You can use the brush to increase, decrease, and smooth the weight.
Through Shift X, you can move, rotate the joint, or load the posture to see if the costume is correctly followed by the bone, or if there is a penetrating part.
When you find that the costume has a hole or an intersection, you can use the sculpt brush to adjust the costume.
There are two types of mixing modes, Grinding and Smooth.
You can press the Ctrl-Tab key to switch to the mixing mode.
Go back to the Everywhere window and switch to the property bar.
UV fill can automatically fill the UV block to prevent overlap and quickly arrange the UV picture.
You can automatically fill the UV block to prevent overlap and quickly arrange the UV picture.
In UV Fill window, enter all the numbers and click on Use.
In the final, the
vanity cookedback function.
In the vanity cookedback window, choose the Macro loan sticker and the environmental light folding sticker options.
The amount of light radiation down the UV affippers means the levels of light in a single pixel.
Uh, uh, this philosophy is somehow
uh, uh, this philosophy is somehow
effect
After you press the button, you can adjust the strength of the hair line sticker by clicking the slider.
When you are ready to upload the file to the Connect page, click the upload button in the Everywhere window.
After setting up the selection, click OK.
This file has been uploaded to Connect. You will go to the page to view it.
Click the FBX download button to download the FBX file.
Live Sync is a feature that connects Marvelous Designer to the virtual machine.
Through this feature, Marvelous Designer can directly import and export files to the virtual machine.
In the virtual machine, go to the window of the CloudAMD Live Sync Editor.
Click the update button to import the costume and the new model to the CloudAMD Live Sync Editor.
When you are sure to save the downloaded assets to the virtual machine's content browser, please select assets.
Then click Save Marker.
Select the static grid or the integrated grid that is stored by animation.
Click Save Marker.
Now the assets can be viewed in the content browser.
You can create the assets in the following scenarios.
You can also import MetalHuman to Marvelous Designer through Live Sync.
Nuclear
At the bottom of the screen, click the file icon.
Click Reload.
Click the Live Sync button in the tool bar at the top, and set it according to the option you need to click.
After clicking the option, the MetaHuman skeleton network with the animation will be successfully imported to Marvelous Designer.
The sewing wrinkle function will make it easier for you to show the details of the outfit.
You can create a sewing wrinkle along the outside, inside, and sewing line.
We can use the sewing wrinkle tool group in the 2D window to create and adjust the sewing wrinkle.
There are three ways to create sewing wrinkle, such as line creation, free creation, and sewing line creation.
After creating the sewing wrinkle in the 2D window, you can see the effect of the sewing wrinkle on the 3D costume.
Switch the object window to Pugrin, that is, the sewing wrinkle type window, and select a sewing wrinkle type.
In the attribute editor at the bottom, you can switch the preset type of sewing wrinkle, or customize the sewing wrinkle style according to your needs.
You can also load the custom sewing wrinkle.
You can also use custom sewing wrinkle as a pattern or hair sticker for the sewing wrinkle.